Ronak Chougule

ronakc@bu.edu | ronakc.info | LinkedIn | +1 (857)-869-3538 | Boston, MA

OBJECTIVE

Dedicated individual with knowledge about Manufacturing and Product Design experience currently looking for summer internships/co-op in respective fields.

SUMMARY

Product Design and Manufacturing Engineer with a background in Mechanical Engineering and experience in improving quality, product design, 3D printing and manufacturing industries. Exhibited ability to design for manufacturability and improvement of product performance. Strong understanding of metal industry such as sand casting, sheet metal fabrication, precision machining and assembly.

EDUCATION

Boston University College of Engineering
Master of Science in Product design and Manufacturing
Vishwakarma Institute of Technology
Pune, India
Bachelors of Technology in Mechanical Engineering
Aug 2020

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Graduate Student Technician

Boston, MA

Boston University

Jan 2022 - Present

- Teaching Assistant for Automated Design and Manufacturing Labs
- Hands on experience with Haas Mills, Gibbs CAM and Universal Robots and grading student work
- Operating CNC machine for demonstrating various machining process to students

Manufacturing Engineer Intern

Kolhapur, India

Chougule Steels

May 2021- Sep 2021

- Maintained furnaces of 1500 kg and 500 kg capacities used for sand casting of heavy parts
- Lead two CAD design projects in production improvement of contract machinery
- Performed analysis on furnace coolant monitoring system used for quality control during the melting process

Product Design Engineer

Kolhapur, India

Wings44

May 2020- May 2021

- Collaborated with technicians and senior engineers to ensure DFM and product performance
- Planned and developed multiple industrial products using solidworks and ergonomic studies
- Programed CNC Laser for precision cutting sheet metal and reducing finishing requirements
- Worked in optimizing hospital functionality by designing ICU beds

SKILLS

Mechanical: Ender 3D printer, Flashforge Finder, Lathe, Arc welding, CNC Lathe Software: CAD: Solidworks, Auto CAD, Onshape, Programming: Gibbs CAM, C, C++

ENGINEERING PROJECTS

MIT Hyperloop III

Sep 2021

- Prototyped Tunneling Machine including guided auger boring with Barbco Tribor, Inc.
- Re-designed new safety system for cutter head and existing guidance mechanism
- Installed information acquisition system for monitoring real-time temperature, position and velocity of steering head
- Lead MIT's Mechanical Engineering team in passing the safety regulations
- Managed onsite operations to set up the Tunneling Machine

Data Acquisition Device for Inspecting Orthopedic Foot Pressure

Aug 2020

- Developed Foot sole with force sensitive resistance's for measuring pressure intensity
- Established a software to collect and analyze the data
- Obtained experimental results to quantify degree of deformation of foot and areas with high pressure